As we've been preparing for our "flipped-classroom" webinar
We decided to experiement with "flipping" our own webinar
And this short video is our attempt to share key concepts about the flipped-classroom model
in preparation for the more interactive webinar.
The flipped classroom requires students to prepare better for class,
and for professors to conduct a more interactive session in the classroom.
The implementation is quite simple,
Professors pre-record a short video
about the class work, share it with their students
Students then watch the video at home at their own pace
and then, the class is used for a more interactive dialog and session.
There are many benefits to this model
First of all, the class work becomes more interactive and engaging
Students arrive better prepared to the class
And many students can learn at their own personal pace
There are however, a few challenges to implementing the flipped-classroom model;
Professors are often intimidated of prerecording these videos.
Many of the professors are also not accustomed to conducting interactive sessions in the class.
Students also do not necessarily like to prepare better for class,
or to interact in the classroom.
There are also practical barriers such as what technology to use when recording and sharing the videos.
At Kaltura, we are sure we can help resolve these challenges and offer ways to address them
in order to offer an optimal flipped-classroom model.
We invite you to join our webinar and learn more this topic.
Thank you.